翻译：屯栗子  小英的小号
翻译：wyk8818  小蛮腰
校对：彼岸荼蘼
总监：somehacker
后期：bongpong
我们重新讲一个老故事
Let us tell an old story a new.
来看看你到底多了解它
And we will see how well you know it.
从前  有两个邻国
Once upon a time there were two kingdoms
它们互相仇视
that were the worst of neighbors.
两国间有着深刻的冲突和鸿沟
So vast the discord between them
据说只有伟大的英雄或可怕的恶人
that is was said only a great hero
才能化解冲突  使它们统一
or a terrible villain might bring them together.
一个王国里  住着你我这样的人
In one kingdom lived folk like you and me
在自负贪婪的国王的统治下
with a vain and greedy king to rule over them.
他们总是不满足于现状
They were forever discontent and envious
觊觎邻居的财富和美好
of the wealth and beauty of their neighbors.
在另一个王国  摩尔森林中
For in the other kingdom, the Moors
生活着各种奇怪而有趣的生物
lived every manner of strange and wonderful creature.
这里不需要国王或皇后的统治
And they needed neither king nor queen
只需要彼此互相信任
but trusted in one another.
在摩尔王国悬崖边的一棵参天大树上
In a great tree on a great cliff in the Moors
生活着一个精灵
lived one such spirit.
你或许以为她只是个小女孩
You might take her for a girl.
但她并不仅仅是普通的女孩子
But she was not just any girl.
她是个仙女
She was a fairy.
好好成长吧
There you go.
她的名字叫玛琳菲森
And her name was Maleficent.
早上好  尚特瓦尔先生  你的车不错
Good morning, Mr. Shantuwell. I love your car.
别别  别这样
No! No! Don't do it!
哈哈  没砸中我
Ha, you missed me!
-早上好  -早上好
- Good morning. - Good morning.
步子真轻盈  姐妹们
Love your walk, girls.
怎么一副大惊小怪的样子
What's all the fuss about?
边境守卫...
The border guards...
凭什么你来说  我想告诉她
Why'd you get to tell her? I want to tell her!
有规矩的  蓝蝶仙子
There are rules, Flittle.
这次我说下次你说
I tell this time, you tell next time.
边境守卫...
The border guards...
不对  你上次就说过了
No, you told last time.
所以这次该我说  绿蕨仙子下次说
So I should tell this time and Thistletwit next time.
到底要说什么
Tell me what?
-好了好了  -多谢你
- Fine! - Ah, thank you.
玛琳菲森  边境守卫...
Maleficent, the border guards...
边境守卫在珠宝湖
The border guards have found a human thief
发现一个人类小偷
at the Pool of Jewels!
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
她总是用那副大翅膀来去匆匆
She's always in a hurry with her big wings.
这里出现了人类
Humans, here.
我希望不会又发生战争
I hope this isn't another war.
我不害怕
I'm not afraid.
再说  我还没有近距离看过人类呢
Besides, I've never seen a human up close.
出来吧
Come out!
不  它们会杀了我的
No! They mean to kill me.
再说  它们都丑死了
And besides, they're hideous to look at.
你真是太没礼貌了
That's extremely rude!
别听他乱说  巴尔萨泽
Don't listen to him, Balthazar.
你帅得很古典
You're classically handsome.
偷东西不对  但我们也不会因此杀人
It's not right to steal, but we don't kill people for it.
出来  马上出来
Come out! Come out this instant!
你成年了吗
Are you fully grown?
没有
No.
我看他只是个小男孩
I believe he's just a boy.
你也只是个小姑娘
And you're just a girl, I think.
你是谁
Who are you?
我叫斯特凡  你又是谁
I'm called Stefan. Who are you?
我是玛琳菲森
I'm Maleficent.
对  我知道
Yes, right.
你得把它还回去
You have to give it back.
还什么回去
Give what back?
早知道你会把它扔掉的话我就不还你了
If I knew you would throw it away, I would have kept it.
我没有把它扔掉
I didn't throw it away.
我把它送回家了  现在再把你送回家
I delivered it home, as I'm going to do for you.
总有一天  我会住在那里  城堡里
Someday, you know, I'll live there. In the castle.
你现在住在哪
Where do you live now?
住谷仓
In a barn.
你的父母是农民吗
So, your parents are farmers then?
我父母亲去世了
My parents are dead.
我的也是
Mine too.
我们会再见面的
We'll see each other again.
你不应该回来的
You really shouldn't come back here, you know.
这样不安全
It's not safe.
如果我决定回来呢  你会在吗
And if I made that choice? If I came back, would you be here?
或许吧
Perhaps.
怎么了
What's wrong?
你的戒指  铁会灼伤仙子的
Your ring! Iron burns fairies.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我喜欢你的翅膀
I like your wings.
玛琳菲森总是想起斯特凡扔掉戒指的样子
Maleficent thought of how Stefan cast away his ring.
他几乎一无所有
He, who had so little in the world
他们的手或许能再次相握
so that their hands might touch again.
她的心灵也受到了感动
And her heart was moved.
那个想要偷珠宝的年轻小偷
Thus did the young thief who had hoped to steal a jewel
却偷走了更珍贵的东西
steal something far more precious.
玛琳菲森
Maleficent!
这么久以后  你终于又来了
After all these weeks, look who came back.
我觉得值得冒险再来一趟
I thought it worth the risk.
你平常都玩些什么
So, what do you do for fun?
斯特凡和玛琳菲森成为了
Stefan and Maleficent
最不可思议的一对朋友
became the most unlikely of friends.
曾经一度  在他们之间
And for a time, it seemed as if in them at least
人类和仙子之间的世代恩怨仿佛消失了
the old hatred between man and fairy had been forgotten.
渐渐地  这种友谊变成了另外一种感情
As it will friendship slowly turned into something else.
在她16岁生日那天
And on her 16th birthday
斯特凡给了玛琳菲森一件礼物
Stefan gave Maleficent a gift.
他说这叫做真爱之吻
He told her it was true love's kiss.
但事实却并非如此
But it was not to be.
岁月流逝
As the years passed
斯特凡的野心使他离开了玛琳菲森
Stefan's ambition called him away from Maleficent
走进了充满诱惑的人类王国
and towards the temptations of the human kingdom.
而玛琳菲森  这个最强大的仙子
While Maleficent, the strongest of the fairies
成为了摩尔王国的守护者
rose to become the protector of the Moors.
玛琳菲森总是一个人在林中徘徊
Maleficent often wandered alone
有时她会想此刻斯特凡在哪里
and sometimes wondered where Stefan might be.
因为她永远无法明白
For she had never understood
人类的贪婪和嫉妒之情
the greed and envy of men.
不过  她即将学到这些
But she was to learn.
因为人类国王听说
For the human king had heard of
摩尔王国中有强大力量正在成长
a growing power in the Moors.
他要打败这股力量
And he sought to strike it down.
士兵们  停下
Guards, hold!
他们就在这里
There they are!
在神秘的摩尔森林中
The mysterious Moors and no one dares to venture
由于害怕里面的魔物  没人敢进去冒险
for fear of the magical creatures that lurk within.
但我要说  击败他们吧
Well, I say: Crush them!
不准前进
Go no further!
国王不会听从
A king does not take orders
一个长着翅膀的怪物的命令
from a winged elf.
对我来说  你不是国王
You are no king to me!
把她的头带到我面前来
Bring me her head.
士兵们  准备
Battalion!
攻击
Attack!
出来吧
Arise
和我一起守护这里
and stand with me!
保持阵型
Hold the line!
是恶灵
It's the dark creatures!
冲啊
Charge!
看招
You!
保护国王
To the king!
你绝对无法占有摩尔王国  永远都不会
You will not have the Moors. Not now, nor ever!
你...
You...
我登上王位时
When I ascended to the throne
曾向百姓许诺
I promised the people one day
终有一天我们会拿下摩尔王国
we would take the Moors
攫取其宝藏
and it's treasures.
你们每个人
Each of you swore
都发誓要效忠于我  因此...
allegiance to me and to that cause...
陛下
Your Majesty.
我在战斗中失败了
Defeated in battle.
这该不会就是我的遗愿吧
Is this to be my legacy?
我知道你们在盼着我死
I see you're waiting for me to die.
我命不久矣  可那又怎样
It won't be long, but what then?
我会选择一个继承者
I will choose a successor
登上王位  照顾我的女儿
to take the throne and care for my daughter.
你们谁值得我信赖
Who among you is worthy?
谁杀了那带翅膀的精灵
Kill the winged creature!
为我报仇
Avenge me!
我死后便可以继承王位
And upon my death you will take the crown.
玛琳菲森
Maleficent.
Maleficent!
和人类一起生活的好吗
So, how is life with the humans?
玛琳菲森  我是来警告你的
Maleficent, I've come to warn you.
他们要杀了你
They mean to kill you.
亨利国王会不惜一切代价攻占这里
King Henry will stop at nothing.
求你相信我
Please, you have to trust me.
他们聊了很多事
They spoke of many things
分别造成的隔阂消失不见
and the years faded away.
她原谅了斯特凡
And she forgave Stefan,
原谅了他的愚蠢和野心
his folly and his ambition.
但是多年前的悲剧再次上演
And all was as it happened long ago.
你渴吗
Are you thirsty?
玛琳菲森
Maleficent?
这是什么
What is this?
陛下  我已经替您报仇血恨
I have avenged you, Sire.
她死了
She is vanquished?
年轻人  你做的很好
Ah, you have done well, my son.
你做到了别人都做不到的事
You have done what others failed to do.
你将会得到奖赏
You will be rewarded.
我必竭尽全力
I shall do my best
成为一个合格的继承者
to be a worthy successor.
国王陛下
Your Majesty.
抓到你了
I got you!
-邪恶的鸟  -变成人吧
- Wicked bird! - Into a man.
魔鬼啊
It's a demon!
你对我做了什么
What have you done to my beautiful south?
你想我让他们活生生打死你吗
Would you rather I let them beat you to death?
-我不确定  -别抱怨了
- I'm not certain. - Stop complaining.
我救了你一命
I saved your life.
请原谅我
Forgive me.
-你叫什么名字  -迪亚瓦
- What do I call you? - Diaval.
为了报救命之恩  我愿做你的仆人
And in return for saving my life I am your servant.
满足你一切需要
Whatever you need.
翅膀
Wings.
我需要你做我的翅膀
I need you to be my wings.
请允许我介绍国王的继承人
I present to you the first of his line:
斯特凡国王殿下
His Royal Highness, King Stefan.
他这样对我
He did this to me
就是为了成为国王
so he would be king.
现在怎么办  主人
Now what, mistress?
是她
She!
她的翅膀呢
Her wings!
是个女孩
It's a girl!
-天啊  是个女孩  -是个女孩
- O, my God, it's a girl! - It's a girl!
-怎样了  -我什么也没看到
- Well? - Well, I saw nothing.
-但是有个...  -什么
- But there's been a... - What?
孩子
child.
斯特凡国王和王后生了个孩子
King Stefan and the Queen have had a child.
他们将举办一场洗礼
There'll be a christening.
据说这会是一场盛宴
They say it's to be a grand celebration.
为孩子...举办盛宴
A grand celebration... for a baby.
多美好啊
How wonderful!
举国上下都来参加洗礼
All manner of folk came to the christening.
包括三位远道而来
Even three of the fairies who sought
寻求和平与美好祝愿的仙子
to foster peace and good will.
-孩子在那里  -最爱小孩子了
- Look, there's the baby! - Love baby!
专注点  别让我说第二遍
Concentrate, please! I'm not telling you again.
致以真切的问候  国王陛下
Greetings, Your Majesty.
我是森林王国里的红叶仙子
I am Knotgrass of the Moorland fair folk.
我是蓝蝶仙子  国王陛下
I am Flittle, Your Kingship.
我是绿蕨仙子  尊贵的国王陛下
And I am Thistletwit, Your Royals.
她们给我们的女儿带来了礼物
They bring gifts for our daughter.
那不是普通的礼物
These are not just any old gifts.
正如你所见  我们会魔法
For you see, we are magic!
而且很招小孩子喜欢
And very good with children.
好吧
Very well.
亲爱的奥萝拉
Sweet Aurora.
我赐予你绝世美貌
I wish for you the gift of beauty.
我愿你永无忧愁
My wish is that you'll never be blue.
幸福一生
Only happy, all the days of your life.
亲爱的孩子
Sweet baby.
我愿你能找到
My wish for you is that you'll find...
玛琳菲森
Maleficent!
还真是高朋满座  斯特凡国王
What a glittering assemblage, King Stefan.
皇室  贵族
Royalty, nobility
绅士  以及
the gentry and...
真是有意思啊
How quaint.
居然还有我的贱民
Even the rabble.
我不得不承认  没收到邀请
I must say I really felt quite distressed
还真挺失望的
of not receiving an invitation.
这里不欢迎你
You're not welcome here.
噢  亲爱的
Oh, dear.
真尴尬
What an awkward situation.
你不会生气了吧
You're not offended?
为什么不会
Why no.
为了表示我并没有恶意
And to show I bear no ill-will
我也应该送个礼物给孩子
I too shall bestow a gift on the child.
我们不想要你的礼物
No! We don't want your gift!
-离公主远点  -走开
- Stay away from the princess! - Yes, stay away!
你们给我听好了
Listen well, all of you.
公主将会拥有
The princess shall indeed
美丽和优雅
grow in grace and beauty.
她遇到的所有人都将爱慕她
Beloved by all who meet her.
这是个很好的礼物
That's a lovely gift.
别这样
Don't do this.
但是
But...
在她十六岁生日日落之前
Before the sun sets on her 16th birthday
她将会被纺锤刺伤手指
she will prick her finger on the spindle of a spinning wheel
陷入死亡般的沉睡
and fall into a sleep like death!
永远也无法醒来
A sleep from which she will never awaken!
玛琳菲森  别这样  我求你了
Maleficent, please don't do this. I'm begging you.
我喜欢你哀求我
I like you begging.
再来一遍
Do it again.
我求你了
I beg you.
好吧
Alright.
公主
The princess can
能从死亡般的沉睡中醒来
be woken from her death sleep.
但只有...
But only by...
真爱之吻才能唤醒她
true love's kiss.
这个魔咒永远不会消失
This curse will last until the end of time!
世间没有任何力量能够改变
No power on earth can change it!
斯特凡国王命令他的手下
King Stefan ordered his men
收集王国上下所有的纺车
to seize every spinning wheel in the kingdom.
将其烧毁
The wheels were broken and burned
这样再也没人能使用它们
that they might never be used
之后将它们扔进城堡最深处的地牢里
and thrown in the deepest dungeon in the castle.
他秘密地将孩子
Secretly he entrusted the safety of the child
托付给那三个仙子保护
to the magic of the pixies
她们将孩子带到偏远的地方抚养
who would take her to a remote hideaway
直到十六年零一天后再回来
for sixteen years and a day.
斯特凡将自己关在城堡里
Stefan shut himself behind the walls of his castle
而他的士兵征战远方
while his soldiers rode far and wide
企图打败玛琳菲森
to hunt Maleficent down.
然而  她为自己的王国建造了围墙
But she made walls of her own
这样  摩尔王国
that the Moors might never again
就再也不会受到人类的威胁
suffered the touch of any human.
而她则沉浸在
And she revelled in the sorrow
对自己魔咒的满足中
that her curse had brought.
三个仙子开始了她们的任务
The fairies began their charge
在树林的一间小屋里抚养奥萝拉
to raise Aurora in a snug little cottage in the woods.
不会吧  那是什么
Oh, no! What is it?
看起来好破旧
Looks dreadful.
走吧
Come on.
孩子太大了
We need a smaller baby.
或者说我们太小了
Or a bigger body.
我们需要一点点伪装
No, what we need is a proper disguise.
什么意思
What do you mean?
我们需要融入孩子的生活  不是吗
Well, we have to blend in, don't we?
我们要足够大才能抚养这个孩子
We have to be big enough to look after this baby.
我们围成圈吧
So, gather around, ladies.
准备
Get ready.
一  二  三  变身
One, two, three. Grow!
太顺利了  非常好
Oh, that went quite well. That's very nice.
不会再有人向我们质疑
Now, there'll be no questions asked.
我们已经不是仙子了
We are no longer fairies.
我们只是三位农家妇女
We are three peasant women,
在树林里抚养着一个孤儿
raising our orphan child in the woods.
再也不准飞了
So, no more flying.
-不能飞吗  -不行不行
- No flying? - No, no.
-也不能使用魔法  -不能用魔法
- And no magic. - No magic?
-是的  -可是我们这荒山野岭的
- Yes, you've heard. - But we in the middle of nowhere.
没人会找到我们
No one is going to find us here.
你在这啊  为什么总是藏起来
There you are. Why are you always hiding?
来吧  我们进去
Come on. Here you go.
真是丑到让人同情
It's so ugly you could almost feel sorry for it.
我讨厌你  小怪兽
I hate you. Beastie.
三位仙子似乎不怎么称职
The fairies were perhaps unequal to their task.
她为什么哭
Why is she crying?
她可能饿了
Maybe she might be hungry.
喂她啊
Then feed her!
就靠这三个东西  她一定会饿死的
It's gonna to starve with those three looking after it.
-干嘛  -你在作弊
- What? - You're cheating.
-我看到了  -我们重新开始
- I saw that. - We're starting again.
随便你
Suit yourself.
贪婪臃肿的老山羊
Greedy, bloated goat!
臃肿的老山羊
Bloated goat!
别闹了
Stop doing that.
我什么也没干
I'm not doing anything.
-有人在搞小动作  -不是我
- Well, someone is. - It's not me.
你俩再捉弄我  我可就忍无可忍了
You two are having a go at me and I will not tolerate...
别闹了
Stop it!
这都是你的错
This is all your fault!
别这样看我  多有趣啊
Oh, come on! That's funny!
随着时间流逝  斯特凡变得愈发偏执
As the days went on, Stefan darkened further consumed
一心想着复仇
by paranoia and vengeance.
-拉下  -传火把
- Pull down! - The torch!
点火
Flame!
准备
Make ready!
发射
Release!
你辜负了我
You failed me.
那堵高墙无法烧毁
The wall cannot be burned.
攻不可破
It is indestructible.
没有东西是攻不可破的
Nothing is indestructible!
无论是高墙  玛琳菲森
Not a wall, not Maleficent!
还是她的魔咒
Not even her curse!
把铁匠给我找来
Bring me the iron workers.
瞧  小怪兽要掉下悬崖了
Oh, look! The little beast is about to fall off the cliff.
干嘛
What?
你好
Hello.
走开  快走
Go away. Go.
走开
Go away.
我不喜欢小孩
I don't like children.
抱抱  抱抱
Up, up.
走吧  走  走  走
Go along. Go, go, go.
正如玛琳菲森所说
As Maleficent had said
奥萝拉长大后美丽又优雅
Aurora did grow in grace and beauty.
漂亮的小鸟
Pretty bird.
她远离了王宫  也早已忘记了那里
Far away from the lofty palace that she remembered not.
随着四季更替
And as the seasons changed
鲜花绽放
and the flowers grew
她也在成长
so did she.
你好
Hello.
真乖
That's it.
她对身边的世界充满了好奇
She wondered at the world about her
也对荆棘丛后的世界充满了好奇
and at what lay beyond the fearsome wall of thorns.
真是个好奇的小家伙
Curious little beastie.
然而她不是惟一想进来的人
But she was not the only one who wished to get through.
是她吗  是玛琳菲森吗
Is that her? Is that Maleficent?
我不知道
I don't know.
把她带来
Bring her to me.
不过是个乡下的傻姑娘
Ah, it's just a silly peasant girl.
是她  是她
It's her! It's her!
你怎么能那么做
How could you do that to me?
你说为了我变什么都行的
You said, anything I need!
是的  那也不能变成狗啊
Yeah, but not a dog!
-是狼  不是狗  -都差不多
- It was a wolf, not a dog. - It's the same thing!
他们肮脏又凶残  还伤害鸟类
They are dirty, vicious and they hunt birds!
好吧  下次我把你变只肉乎乎的虫子
Fine, next time I'll turn you into a mealy worm.
我宁愿做只肉乎乎的虫子
Well, I'll be a mealy worm gladly!
什么都行  除了肮脏可恶的...
Anything but a filthy, stinking...
我很好奇...
I wonder...
我知道你在那儿
I know you're there.
别害怕
Don't be afraid.
我可没有害怕
I'm not afraid.
那就出来啊
Then come out.
那么你会害怕的
Then you will be afraid.
不  我不会
No, I won't.
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
是吗
Do you?
你是我的仙女教母
You're my fairy godmother.
-什么  -仙女教母啊
- What? - Fairy godmother.
你一直在关注着我的生活
You've been watching over me my whole life.
我知道你一直在我身边
I've always known you were close by.
你怎么知道
How?
你的影子  它从我儿时起就跟着我
Your shadow. It's been following me ever since I was small.
无论我去哪里  你的影子都和我在一起
Wherever I went, your shadow is always with me.
我记得你  漂亮的小鸟
I remember you, pretty bird.
这是迪亚瓦
This is Diaval.
你好  奥萝拉
Hello, Aurora.
你很小的时候我就认识你了
I've known you since you were a little one.
这里和我想的一模一样
It's everything I imagined it would be.
真是美极了
Oh, it's just so beautiful!
我一直想来...
I've always wanted to come...
晚安  小家伙
Goodnight, beastie.
你在嘲笑我
You mock me.
我知道你在干什么
I know what you're doing.
我很清楚你在干什么
I know exactly what you're doing.
陛下  皇后想见您
Sire, your presence has been requested by the Queen.
我想一个人待着
Leave me.
陛下  她情况不太好
Sire, she is not well.
侍从们担心她撑不过今晚了
The nurses are fearful that she won't make it through the night.
你看不出来我正在和别人讲话吗
Can you not see we're having a conversation?
一旦魔咒失效  玛琳菲森就会来找我
When the curse fails, Maleficent will come for me.
而那时  我也将做好准备
And on that day, I will be ready.
她们真美
They're so beautiful.
我收回魔咒
I revoke the curse.
让它消失吧
Let it be no more.
我收回魔咒
I revoke the curse.
让它消失吧
Let it be no more.
我收回魔咒
I revoke my curse!
让它消失吧
Let it be no more!
我收回魔咒
I revoke my curse!
让它消失吧
Let it be no more!
这个魔咒永远不会消失
This curse will last until the end of times
世间没有任何力量能够改变
No power on earth can change it.
所有仙子都有翅膀吗
Do all the fair people have wings?
大部分有
Most do.
那为什么你没有
Then, why don't you?
其他的仙子都可以飞
All the other fairies fly.
我曾经有  但它们被偷走了
I had wings once. They were stolen from me.
我只能说这么多
That's all I wish to say about it.
它们是什么颜色的
What color were they?
它们大吗
Were they big?
很大  我走路时它们就拖在后面
So big they dragged behind me when I walked.
而且它们很有力
And they were strong.
它们能带着我直上云端  迎风飞翔
They could carry me above the clouds and into the headwinds.
而且它们从不退缩
And they never faltered.
从来没有过
Not even once.
我可以信任它们
I could trust them.
她要来了  她要来了
She's coming. She's coming.
你的手下呢
Where are your workers?
在睡觉  陛下
In their beds, Majesty.
让他们马上起来干活
Get them back to work without delay.
他们已经累坏了  陛下
They're exhausted, Sire.
但我会让他们天一亮就开干
But I'll have them back to work at first light.
我要他们现在就起来
I need them back to work now.
现在还是凌晨
It's the wee hours.
是啊
Aye.
还是凌晨
It is the wee hours.
叫他们起来
So, wake them up.
陛下
Sire?
叫他们起来
So, wake them up!
让他们现在就去干活
And get them back to work now!
我们没时间了  快去
We're running out of time! Go on!
奥萝拉
Aurora!
过来
Come here.
坐下
Sit.
我有些事要告诉你
There is something I need to tell you.
什么事
What is it?
这世上有个恶魔
There is an evil in this world.
而我保护不了你
And I cannot keep you from it.
我都快十六了  教母
I'm almost 16, godmother.
我能照顾好自己
I can take care of myself.
我明白
I understand.
-我不是要和你说这个  -我有个计划
- That's not what I have to say to you. - I have a plan.
等我长大了  就和你一起住在这里
When I grow up, I'm going to live here in the Moors with you.
这样我们就能相互照顾
Then we can look after each other.
你不用等到长大
You don't have to wait until you're older.
你现在就可以住在这里
You could live here now.
我很乐意
Then I will!
我要睡在树上  吃莓子和坚果
I'll sleep in a tree and eat berries and black nuts.
所有的精灵都会成为我的朋友
And all the fair people will be my friends.
我将无忧无虑地过我的一生
I'll be happy here for the rest of my life.
我明天就去和姑母们说
I'm going to tell my aunties tomorrow.
明天就去
Until tomorrow.
我真是太激动了
Oh, I'm so excited!
姑母
Aunties.
我快十六了  我想过自己的生活
I'm almost 16. I need a life of my own.
我是非常爱你们的
No, I love you very much.
但现在是时候告别了
But it's time to say goodbye.
你们对我很好
You've been very good to me.
除了会不小心喂我蜘蛛
Except the time you accidentally fed me spiders.
你好
Hello.
抱歉打扰你
I'm sorry to bother you,
我要去斯特凡国王的城堡
but I'm on my way to King Stefan's castle
很不幸我迷路了
and I've become hopelessly lost.
你能帮我吗
Can you help me?
抱歉  都是我的错
I'm sorry, that was my fault.
我不该闯进...
I rushed into...
原谅我
Forgive me.
从那边走
It's that way.
就能到城堡
The castle.
-你叫什么  -我叫菲利普
- What's your name? - It's Phillip.
你好  菲利普
Hello, Phillip.
-你叫什么  -奥萝拉
- What's yours? - Aurora.
你好  奥萝拉
Hello, Aurora.
很高兴见到你  再次向你表示抱歉
Well, it was nice meeting you and once again my apologies
我真是太莽撞了
for being such a clumsy fool.
-我原谅你了  -太好了
- You're forgiven. - That's good.
我该走了
Well, I'll best be off then.
再见
Goodbye.
你还会回来吗
Will you be back this way?
必然回来  风雨无阻
Nothing could stop me.
-那我很快就会见到你  -非常快
- Then I'll see you soon. - Very soon.
再见  菲利普
Goodbye, Phillip.
再见...暂时再见
Goodbye... for now.
别这样
Stop doing that.
那男孩儿就是答案
Well? That boy is the answer!
-不是的  迪亚瓦  -是
- No, Diaval. - Yes!
真爱之吻  记得吗  可以打破魔咒
True love's kiss, remember? It can break the spell.
真爱之吻
True love's kiss?
你还不明白吗
Have you not worked it out yet?
我这样下咒就是因为世上根本没那玩意
I cursed her that way, because there is no such thing.
你可能这么想  但是奥萝拉呢
Well, that might be how you feel. But what about Aurora?
那个男孩儿是惟一的机会了
That boy could be her only chance.
毕竟那是她的命运
It's her fate, anyway.
来啊  随便把我变成什么
Go ahead. Turn me into whatever you want.
鸟也好  虫也好  我都不在乎了
A bird, a worm. I don't care anymore.
我好开心啊  我们明天就能走了
I'm so happy we're leaving tomorrow.
你明天哪也去不了
You're not leaving tomorrow.
明天就是奥萝拉16岁生日了
Tomorrow is Aurora's 16th birthday.
斯特凡叫我们在她生日后一天再带她回去
And Stefan told us to take her back the day after her birthday.
不对  他说的是她生日当天
No, he said, on her birthday.
不对  是她生日后一天
No, after her birthday.
-当天  -后一天
- On. - After.
当天  当天  当天
On, on, on!
后一天  后一天
After, after!
-当天  当天  -后一天  后一天
- On, on! - After, after!
住手
Stop it!
干吗
What?
胆大包天
How could you?
我要跟你们说件事
I need to talk to you about something.
好呀  亲爱的  什么事
O yes, sweetie, what is it?
很抱歉跟你们说这件事
I'm sorry to have to tell you this.
但我明天就16岁了
But I'll be 16 tomorrow.
没错  快  把这放下
Oh, yes, quick, put it here.
我要离开家了
I'm leaving home.
听着  小姑娘
See here, young lady.
我在这个小破屋里跟这俩傻瓜
I did not spend 16 years in this miserable hovel
一块住了十六年...闭嘴
with these two imbeciles... hush!
可不是为了在最后一天功亏一篑的
So that you could ruin it on the last day!
我们这就把你带回到你父亲身边
We are taking you back to your father without...
我父亲
My father?
你跟我说我父母都死了
You told me my parents were dead.
我想你最好还是过来坐下
I think you better come and sit down.
仙女教母
Fairy godmother!
我在这
I'm here.
你准备什么时候才告诉我  我受了诅咒
When were you going to tell me that I'm cursed?
这是真的吗
Is it true?
是的
It is.
我的婶婶们说是个邪恶的仙女干的
My aunts said it was an evil fairy.
我...我不记得她的名字了
I... I can't remember her name.
她们说  她叫...
They said... that is was...
玛琳菲森
Maleficent.
是你吗
Is that you?
你是玛琳菲森吗
Are you Maleficent?
不  别碰我
No! Don't touch me.
你是世界上最邪恶的人
You're the evilest in the world.
居然是你
It's you!
找到那个男孩
Find the boy!
所有人去东翼
All the men to the east wing now!
门口不要有守卫
There should be no guards at the gate.
我要她走进来时...
I want her to walk in...
抱歉打扰了  国王陛下
Sorry to disturb, Your Majesty.
我们在城门外发现了这个女孩
We found this girl at the gate.
她说她是公主
She claims to be the princess.
父亲  是我  我是奥萝拉
Father, it's me, Aurora!
你长得跟你母亲一模一样
You look just like your mother.
她们提早一天把你带回来了
They brought you back a day too soon.
我都跟那三个蠢货讲过了
I told those three idiots!
把她锁到她房间里去
Lock her up in her room.
去
Go.
准备好网  玛琳菲森要来了
Prepare the net. Maleficent is coming.
又变小真是太好了
It's so good to be small again!
看我的脚  我爱我的小脚
Look at my feet! I love my tiny little feet!
集中精力  我们必须找到奥萝拉
Pay attention! We have to find Aurora!
国王非要了我们的脑袋不可
Oh, the king will have our heads!
等一下
Wait!
公主
Princess.
-我在找一个女孩  -当然
- I'm looking for a girl. - Of course you are.
我需要匹马
I need a horse.
快点  迪亚瓦
Come on, Diaval!
快点  迪亚瓦  再快点
Faster, Diaval! Faster!
诅咒应验了
It's done.
他们撤走了守卫  他在里面等你呢
They pulled the guards. He's waiting for you in there.
如果我们进去  就不可能再活着出来了
If we go inside those walls, we'll never come out alive.
那你就别跟来
Then don't come.
这不是你的战斗
It's not your fight.
还真是非常感谢你啊
Well, thank you very much.
我需要你  迪亚瓦
I need you, Diaval.
没有你我办不到  迪亚瓦
I can't do this without you, Diaval.
我能听见你讲话
I can hear you.
看看她
Look at her.
看看你们干的好事
Look at what you've done.
她只是睡着了而已
She's only sleeping.
你说她只是睡着了而已
She's only sleeping, you say?
她只是睡着了而已
She's only sleeping.
她只不过是睡着了  永远睡着了
She's only sleeping forever!
那个吻呢
What about the kiss?
没错  真爱之吻
Yes, true love's kiss.
真爱根本就不存在
True love does not exist.
可这是她唯一的机会了  国王陛下
But it's her only chance, Your Majesty.
主人
Mistress.
我们怎么办呢
What are we going to do?
我们总不能放弃吧  振作点  姑娘们
Well, we can't give up, can we? Come on, girls!
可我们根本不知道从何入手啊
But we don't even know where to start!
真爱又不是天上掉下来的馅饼
True love doesn't just fall from trees, you know.
抱歉
Pardon me.
不好意思  我都不知道自己这是在哪
I'm embarrassed to say that I don't know where I am.
你在斯特凡国王的城堡里
In King Stefan's castle.
我就是想到这里来的
This is where I was meant to be.
虽然我不记得我是怎么过来的了
Although I can't recall how I got here.
-你来干吗  -我父亲派我来见国王
- Why have you come? - My father sent me to see the king.
-你父亲是谁  -奥弗斯戴的国王约翰
- Who is your father? - King John of Ofsted.
他是王子
A prince!
奥萝拉
Aurora.
他认识她
He knows her.
她怎么睡了
Why is she sleeping?
她被施了魔法
She's trapped in an enchantment.
她很美吧
Isn't she beautiful?
她是我见过的最美的姑娘
The most beautiful girl I have ever seen.
你想吻她吗
Do you want to kiss her?
非常想
Very much.
那就吻吧
Just go on then.
这不好吧  我们都不熟
I'm not sure about it. I barely know her.
只见过一次面
We've only met once.
你难道没听说过一见钟情吗
Haven't you ever heard of love at first sight?
吻她啊  快啊
Kiss her! Go on.
你说她被施了魔法吗
An enchantment, you say?
快吻她
Kiss her!
你没做对
You didn't do it properly!
这本该就是真爱之吻了
It's supposed to be true love's kiss!
-我很肯定就是他的  -你们干嘛
- I was certain he was the one! - What are you doing?
我们得继续找
We have to keep looking.
我就说吧
I told you.
我不祈求你的原谅
I will not ask your forgiveness.
因为我对你的所作所为不值得宽恕
Because what I have done to you is unforgivable.
我被仇恨
I was so lost
和复仇蒙蔽了双眼
in hatred and revenge.
甜美的奥萝拉
Sweet Aurora.
你偷走了我仅剩的真心
You stole what was left of my heart.
而现在我永远地失去你了
And now I have lost you forever.
我发誓  只要我还活着
I swear, no harm will come to you
你就不会受到丝毫伤害
as long as I live.
我将没有一天
And not a day shall pass
不想念你的笑颜
that I don't miss your smile.
你好  教母
Hello, godmother.
你好  小怪物
Hello, beastie.
还说没有真爱
No true love.
她来了  陛下
She's here, Sire.
我们现在要回摩尔王国吗
Are we going back to the Moors now?
如果你愿意的话
If that is what you wish.
-住手  -躲开
- Stop! - Get back!
变龙
Into a dragon.
快跑  奥萝拉
Run, Aurora!
够了
Enough!
感觉怎么样
How does it feel?
成了无翼的仙女
To be a fairy creature without wings?
待在一个不属于你的世界里
In a world where you don't belong!
杀了她
Kill her!
射死她
Shoot her!
都结束了
It's over.
玛琳菲森拆掉了她的荆棘墙
Maleficent brought down her wall of thorns
摘掉了她的皇冠
and took off her crown
并邀请奥萝拉看摩尔王国曾经的景象
and she invited Aurora to see how the Moors had been once.
那是很久以前
Long ago
那时的玛琳菲森还是个孩子
when Maleficent was but a child
内心一片光明
and her heart was bright.
现在一切又回到了最初的模样
For now, it was again.
故事还不止如此
But that was not all.
她在那  快点  他们等着呢
Over there she is. Hurry up, they're waiting!
等等我
Wait for me!
我们把这顶皇冠献给我们的小奥萝拉
We present this crown to our little Aurora
我们为她牺牲了最好的青春年...
for whom we have sacrificed the best years of our...
算了
Never mind.
我们的王国统一了
Our kingdoms have been unified.
你们有皇后了
You have your Queen!
你们看  故事和之前听过的不太一样吧
So you see, the story is not quite as you were told.
我最了解了
And I should know.
因为我就是大家口中的睡美人
For I was the one they called Sleeping Beauty.
最后  我的王国统一了
In the end, my kingdom was united.
不是像传说中的那样
Not by a hero or a villain
被恶人或是英雄统一的
as legend had predicted.
她是一个善恶兼具的人
But one who was both hero and villain.
她的名字就是
And her name was
玛琳菲森
Maleficent.
沉睡魔咒